Robert M. Vogel and Helena E. Wright Collection of Textile Industry Photographs 6863 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Robert M. Vogel and Helena E. Wright Collection of Textile Industry Photographs
1916-1929
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Robert M. Vogel
Helena E. Wright
6863 P
0.11 cubic feet
0.1 linear ft.
Gelatin silver print, photographs.
Photographs of Nashawena Mills, New Bedford, Massachusetts.
10070761
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, October 18, 2017
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, December 06, 2017
Biographical / Historical
Incorporated in 1909, the Nashawena Mills was making fine cotton and silk goods and jacquard novelties in 1929, although it branched out into other goods later on. The mills appear to have gone out of business by 1952.
Scope and Contents
Interior and exterior views of Nashawena Mills, New Bedfort, Massachusetts. Included are images of the buildings, machinery, male and female workers, and male executives.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6863: Robert M. Vogel and Helena E. Wright Collection of Textile Industry Records
Cotton; Cotton machinery; Cotton manufacture; Executives; Industries; Women employees; Labor; Male employees; Silk; Silk industry; Silk industry -- Employees; Textile factories; Textile industry; Textile machinery; Textile workers; Weaving; Women silk industry workers; Women textile workers; New Bedford (Mass.); Burton, John L.; Nashawena Mills (New Bedford, Mass.)
10070761
- Nashawena Mills Photographs, 1916-1929 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Personnel of the Nashawena Mills, 1929; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    June 17, 1929. Gelatin silver print. Image depicts the management personnel posed in front of what is presumably the Nashawena Mills building. Two rows of men in shirts and ties; the back row has 13 men standing, the front row has 9 seated. Written on the photo is "Personnel of the Nashawena Mills, New Bedford, Mass. John L. Burton, Agent, June, 27-1929" but it is unknown if Burton is in this photo or which one of the men might be him. 42.5 x 17.5 cm.
  - Item 2: Exterior view of the Nashawena Mills, 1916; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print. Image shows exterior view of mills, with four-story brick building on the left, and a two-story building on the right; complex takes up most of a city block. 21.5 x 17 cm. (w/out mount); 30.5 x 25.5 cm. (w/mount).
  - Item 3: Warping room, 1916; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print. Image shows posed group of female workers and two male overseers in the warping room; warping machinery on either side of group. 21.5 x 17 cm. (w/out mount); 30.5 x 25.5 cm. (w/mount).
  - Item 4: Spooling room, 1916; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print. Image shows posed group of male workers and boys in front of the spooling machinery; two supervisors in the group. 20.5 x 15.5 cm. (w/out mount); 30.5 x 25.5 cm. (w/mount).
  - Item 5: Slashing Room, 1916; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print. Image shows interior view of slashing room with male workers posed in front of slashers. 20.5 x 15.5 cm. (w/out mat); 30.5 x 25.5 cm. (w/mat).
  - Item 6: Employees of the Nashawena Mills, 1916; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print. Image shows posed group of male and female (primarily female) employees in an interior room of the Nashawena Mills. 20.5 x 15.5 cm. (w/out mount); 30.5 x 25.5 cm. (w/mount).
  - Item 7: Office of the Nashawena Mills, 1916; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print. Image shows male worker seated at desk and female worker standing in office of mill; calendar turned to March 1916. 20.5 x 15.5 cm. (w/out mount); 30.5 x 25.5 cm. (w/mount).
  - Item 8: Spooling room with female employees, 1916; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print. Image shows female workers standing beside machines; bins of spools are on the left. 20.5 x 15.5 cm. (w/out mount); 30.5 x 25.5 cm. (w/mount).
  - Item 9: Spooling room with four employees, 1916; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, ca. 1916. Image shows two female employees standing by machines and two male overseers in foreground of spooling room of Nashawena Mills. 22 x 17 cm. (w/out mount); 30.5 x 25.5 cm. (w/mount).